Where'd it go?
Here we go.
Okay,
terrific.
So my name is Michael Merriam.
I work with games and epistemologies
and games and perception.
This often means
working with games and pedagogy.
And this is called.
This has had a few titles.
It is now called course correction.
And it is about nodes.
So I'm briefly
mentioning the wonderful electronic
literature and digital humanities
work and tradition and trajectory
that kind of supports and explains
the importance of what
I'm going to talk about, which is quizzes
as a form of interactive nonfiction.
And without this
that I'm just gesturing at here, it's
going to sound like I'm
just giving tips or best practices
or fun things to think about.
If you're an educator and you create
a quiz, it's not really true.
It's kind of weirder
and more important than that.
I'm saying
that the quiz can't be non-fictional.
It's too much like a game, it's too ludic,
and I hope to
demonstrate a little bit of how.
But rather than harp on that,
I want to look at how game mechanics,
especially when they involve interactive
text, are games
that use questions as nodes
and that use them game and mechanically.
And as long as that's been around,
they've been doing research
into the potential of questions
and we should learn from them.
Hope to demonstrate why this is.
I've got so many anecdotes, of course,
but this is a to in virology
and very frustrated.
Told me he cannot figure out
how to word the question so he doesn't get
what he used to perceive
as smart aleck answers like this.
He would say,
explain how you used a graph to a Ravager
answer, the student would say.
I looked at it
to his surprise, when he talked with
some of these students
one on one, he realized
sometimes these are not sarcastic.
They are sincere, right?
There are cultural contexts
where one does not
give more information than one is asked
for, where it should be that literal.
So I was developing this because
during Covid, I had one of those classes
satisfied a lot of guys.
I was trying to make it accessible
to everyone.
I of course made it worse,
but I could have made it
very clear to everyone if I could just
have talked to them for five minutes.
There wasn't a way to do that.
They weren't going to come to the virtual,
you know, intro lecture reliably.
Discussion posts were okay,
but they're kind of phoning it in.
What they would do is
if there was a quiz then and it was
had to be completed by a certain time,
they pretty much always did it in a panic.
That enabled me to simulate
a conversation with them.
Because there's me asking a question.
It's a harmless one.
They see that no matter what they do,
they're going to get 100 on this quiz.
And that enabled me
to have that conversation.
What it didn't enable was a back and forth
based on what they said,
because it's just marking them right or
wrong and advancing to the next question.
So I had to do a lot of bizarre things
to kind of fake.
It made me wish
the LMS had more functionality.
And everything I'm talking about today
is also relies on this digital humanities
theoretical tradition, because writing
so technically and precisely about it,
that also means it can be coded
and it can be coded to comply
with administrative standards.
That's really important.
So I'm going to look at question types.
And then I'm going to look at game
mechanics that do the same thing.
And how the game mechanic teaches us
the potential of that question type.
We didn't see so true or false questions.
This is from a high school biology quiz.
And it is not from AP bio,
and it is not from honors biology.
This is we're going
to get through this biology right.
So the instructor wanted very much
to make sure they weren't missing
some of the crucial details.
True or false.
Osmosis is diffusion through a membrane.
Last time I gave this talk
there was so much debate around it,
which astonished me
because I thought for sure
the answer was true.
In this particular quiz,
the answer is false. Why?
Because most is diffusion of water
through a membrane.
Okay, I get it.
I disagree. It's diffusion.
It's through a membrane.
These are true. It has to be true.
But it's not I'm not the teacher.
Here's the thing though. The
the sort of
idea of a modest witness
or a neutral standpoint isn't so.
And again, rather than harp on that, I'm
going to look at what
I would have been asked to do in my day
job as a narrative designer,
what kind of solutions
I would be expected to bring to this,
and it would probably be
to give it a character skin.
Okay, so let's say that the teacher wanted
the answer to be false.
That was what they thought was correct.
It was that false.
It's not because we want to avoid
the misconception.
Let's say we skin it
as Doctor Victoria Frankenstein.
She's saying, I'm so close, but are these
facts in my lab notebook reliable?
I fear I have overlooked some detail.
Am I missing something?
Will you help? I'm desperate for your aid.
True or false?
Osmosis. Diffusion. To remember it. Right.
So she's dramatizing the fact that we're
afraid we've left something out.
And this discloses.
And some teachers might object.
It gives away what we're looking for.
But let's say they didn't want that.
Let's say they don't want details.
They want just the basics.
The character of skin would be something
like the Jack Webb character from Dragnet,
you know, never mind the fancy details.
We know you got some kind of degree.
Just the facts, please.
The law is the law.
Either way, it's osmosis, diffusion
through a membrane or false.
Okay, so the core concept is recognized.
It is true. These are.
Fictional skins.
So it seems incompatible with nonfiction
and therefore incompatible
with teaching a science.
However, these narrative skins
do not add a fictional layer.
They remove a fictional layer.
The fiction was that the test was neutral.
The fiction was that
the question was impartial,
and once you have this, you're
disclosing the bias.
It's true.
You're doing it in a fun way.
But this is also the most efficient way,
because without a character personality
that communicates
all of this context, body language stuff
that you might be able to do yourself
if it was a synchronous class, right?
Without all that, it would just take
too many words to explain, you know,
to disclose your standpoint and why
you're asking and, and all of that.
But more importantly,
a true false question is a branch.
It is a binary branch.
And imagine if we had a spatial sense
and we already kind of
do when we talked to students,
we talk about getting them back on track.
We say, you're lost, right?
We say, I wish you would take me with you
in this paragraph.
Right?
So imagine if instead of saying, Is Iago
the villain of Othello, is a fellow
a bad man, or is he a weak man?
Okay, now
we've got two different ways of thinking.
And you as an instructor,
in this case, you're saying.
Fair enough. If you wish.
This was more about,
you know, thinking about it deeply
and the nuance and the ins and outs,
we got a path that goes there.
Right?
And if you're not, if you're like, look,
I read it.
What do you want from me?
We can go that way too.
And the questions are,
well, that's
another way in which they can be nodal.
It can be a geographic conception
of it. So.
Let's look at another game mechanic
for multiple choice right.
Let's think about branching dialog.
And some of you guys are familiar
with this Mass Effect wheel.
It means that when the protagonist of Mass
Effect is in any situation.
This is the dialog.
But this button
is always going to be kind of charming.
This button is always going
to be kind of hostile.
They're mapped reliably,
consistently onto something like that.
That's an innovation
that came out of games.
This is what it would be in an RPG.
It can be any situation,
but this one is always going to be polite.
This one's going to be curious,
neutral, hostile.
Let's look at it in nonfiction.
Let's look at it in math.
What is 20 minus
four times two minus three?
A lot of people would be shocked
at how much the answers might vary.
Okay, let's say I have mapped it so that A
is always the answer you'll get
if you focus on order of operations.
B is what you'll get
if you always just try
to get to the answer without overthinking.
C is if you focus on the most recent
concept and deeds.
If you assume it's a trick question, right
this way,
when we can see after 20 questions
what kind of error they're making
most often, right, we'll be able to say
and even tell them at the end of the quiz.
It looks like you're assuming
that we are only reviewing the last week.
Like let's say, in the last week
they had learned that a negative times
a negative makes it positive.
They would calculate this to be 15, right?
If that's what they're focused on.
It is in fact an order of operations
issue.
It is this one.
And of course you don't have to disclose.
You can still randomize where they show up
visually in terms of the,
you know,
in case you don't want students to
to gain the system, but the LMS itself
could still keep track of that for you
and could still diagnose either for you
or even student facing if you wanted to.
And that's that's a functionality
that we wouldn't arrive
at, I don't think, unless we looked at
what games are using it for.
So in the interest of time,
let's just talk about word problems
really quickly.
And I got to slide this down okay.
So I actually had ChatGPT
generate a word problem for me then.
Look they are narrative right.
The characters are poorly handled
and the hypothetical people in them
seem irrational.
So I said to generate an obnoxious word
problem on a 10th grade math test,
one where the protagonist need for
the answer is unconvincing,
and the difficulty of the calculation
makes us not want to give the protagonist
what they want.
I obviously I'm biasing the heck
out of this, but this is my point.
It said, okay, Crispin's
emergency chocolate.
Crispin has decided the only acceptable
way to announce his candidacy
for sophomore class treasurer is to stand
beneath a rented chocolate fountain.
At exactly the moment it contains
42l of chocolate.
He has not explained why
this will make anyone trust him with money
at 8 a.m.,
the fountain contains 18 leaders.
You see where this is going?
He wants to know the earliest time
at which to make his announcement.
So a narrative designer
is going to be able to say,
the problem here is not
only do we not understand
the States for Crispin,
but we are now hostile to him
because this is not just absurd,
it's also trivial.
It's very unimportant.
And he's making a demand of us
that we do not want to fill.
So I'm going to give another extreme
example.
It's going to demonstrate
what a narrative designer would do.
It's a little too much for what
we do in a class.
But let's how about this Crispin is on
trial for a crime he did not commit.
The crime occurred at 6:33 p.m.
at a store one and a half miles
east of the station.
Security footage shows him
boarding a westbound train at 618.
You had the idea to submit to the court
the distance Crispin
was from the scene of the crime
when it occurred, showing all work.
The court will check your work
and if your math is wrong,
Crispin will be found guilty.
They don't have to appreciate
what you're doing.
They don't have to think it's
funny or fun, and it can be absurd,
but they do have to understand it
and they have to understand
why it's important.
All right, they did it.
And I've seen every variation of this
where they're like,
I really resent what you've done here.
But the answer is this to like,
okay, that's fair.
That's fine, I like it.
I will also mention,
unless they're working on
an educational game, which forces them
to prioritize things,
most designers will say the task
and the diagnosis of the premise
must simulate, not replicate,
but simulate a meaningful involvement
of the math you're asking them to do.
It's a competence fantasy, right?
So that's why you really shouldn't
have asteroids with numbers on them.
And then an equation and shoot the right
asteroid because that's not real.
Right? Okay.
So just about out of time.
So I'm going to speed through this.
I'm trying to imagine beyond
what I've been able to think of.
And starting in 2023, I was started
making a database of questions
in Emily Johnson's class, question types
from all different kinds of games.
And I'm interested in
what's two beyond, like Marco Polo.
That seems to be we're
trying to find where they are. Right.
And I've got
a list of the known unknowns
that will be available on my website.
Ludo ception perception through Gamescom.
These are the references.
Thank you so much for your kind attention
and I'm
all done.
All right,
so that concludes the presentations part.
And we have technically
about three minutes left.
However there's not a panel
waiting for us other than.